Maybe we were using the wrong tool all along,
也许一直以来我们用错了工具
so let me show you another tool to use, using
所以让我来告诉你另外一个可以使用地工具， 运用
a fresh new example. What you see here is a map
一个全新的范例。 你在这里看到的 是一张荷兰地图
of the Netherlands. This is where we are, we are in Delft.
。 我们就在这里， 我们在代尔夫特。
Suppose I want to take the train
假设我想坐火车
from Delft to Groningen, that's here.
从代尔夫特到格罗宁根，就是这儿。
So there's no direct train and we can see this on the map,
那么我们可在这个地图上看到没有直达的火车，
because the trains are the black lines on the map
因为 在地图上的黑线代表火车
and there's no direct train from Delft to Groningen.
而从代尔夫特到 格罗宁根没有直达列车。
So how am I going to make this travel? I have two different options:
所以，我应该怎么办？ 我有两个不同的选项：
either I take the train to Leiden, that's here,
我可以坐火车到莱顿， 就是在这里，
or I take the train to Rotterdam, that's there,
或者我可以坐火车去鹿特丹，也就是那儿，
and from there I can take a direct train
并从那里乘坐直达列车
to Groningen, so either I go this way or
到格罗宁根，所以要么我走这条路不然就是
I go that way. And if I want to calculate what the best
走那条路。 如果我想计算 最好的
option is, I also need to add weights to my arrows.
选择是什么，我还需要把权数添加到 箭头上。
So this one from Delft to Leiden will take me
所以从代尔夫特到莱顿的路程将耗费
21 minutes, from Delft to Rotterdam,
21分钟，而从代尔夫特到鹿特丹的将耗费
will take me 12. And then from
12分钟。 然后从
Rotterdam to Groningen is two hours and
鹿特丹到格罗宁根则是两个小时，
39 minutes and this one
39分钟而这一个
is two hours and 28 minutes. So I can calculate
是两小时28分钟。 这样我就可以
my total travel time by summing these two
通过总和这两趟行程的时间
and summing those two and for this representation
和总和另外两趟行程的时间来计算我所需的总时间，
I don't even need the map anymore. If I have my graph,
我甚至不需要地图了。 如果 我用所有的数字连接
my lines and my nodes with all the numbers attached,
我的图表，路线，结点，
I can just delete the whole map. There we go!
我可以删除整个地图。 就是这样！
And this is now a correct representation of my problem.
现在这是我问题的正确的展示 。
I have a node Leiden, Rotterdam, Delft
我有一个莱顿，鹿特丹，代尔夫特
and Groningen, and I have arrows between them,
和格罗宁根的结点，在它们中间我有箭头 ，
this one, that one and those two and those arrows.
这个，那个，那两个和 这些箭头。
have weights. And this is called a graph, a representation of the problem
标有权数。 而这就是所谓的曲线图， 用结点和箭头来展示问题
in terms of nodes and arrows.
。
And of course, you have imagined that we can use this same
当然，你已经想到我们 可以使用同样的
scenario, the same method, to analyse our Bacon problem.
方案，同样的方法，来分析我们 的Bacon问题。
Let's have a look at the Bacon problem, how it looks like in a spreadsheet.
让我们来看看培根问题， 它在电子表格 中看起来是什么样子。
We have actors and movies and actors
我们有演员，电影
that have played in movies, and I can draw this problem
和曾出演电影的演员，我可以 将问题
like a graph too, like I did it with the map of the Netherlands.
画成图像，就像我曾对荷兰地图做的那样。
I can say here's Kevin Bacon and he has played
我可以说这是凯文·培根，他出演
in the movie 'Crazy Stupid Love', I just draw a line
过电影“ 疯狂盲目的爱情 '，我只是
between the actor and the movie. And I can repeat this,
在演员和电影间画上一条线 我可以 重复这个行为，
I can add Emma Stone and Julianne Moore
我可以添加艾玛·斯通和朱丽安·摩尔
because they have played in 'Crazy Stupid Love' too. And I can continue this process
因为他们都曾出演“疯狂盲目的 爱情”。 而我可以继续这个过程
and make an entire graph of the problem that we are analyzing:
和把我们正在分析的问题做成一个图表：
Who has played in which movie? And because we're representing it like a
谁在哪部电影中演过？ 而正 因为我们将它做成一个
graph,
图表，
you see that, immediately, your view on the problem changes,
你看到的是，你对此问题的看法 将马上产生变化，
because it gets really easy now to calculate the
因为现在 计算
Bacon distance from Bacon to another actor, because we can just
从培根到另一位演员的培根距离变得很容易，因为我们可以只
traverse
研究
the lines in the graph and that's what we're going to explore
图中的线，这就是 我们在接下来的
in the next video.
视频将要探索的。